<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/</id><title>Techno Tim</title><subtitle>Documentation for Techno Tim YouTube videos for all your copy pasta needs!</subtitle> <updated>2021-12-21T13:00:47-06:00</updated> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> <uri>https://techno-tim.github.io/</uri> </author><link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://techno-tim.github.io/feed.xml"/><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en-US" href="https://techno-tim.github.io/"/> <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator> <rights> © 2021 Techno Tim </rights> <icon>/assets/img/favicons/favicon.ico</icon> <logo>/assets/img/favicons/favicon-96x96.png</logo> <entry><title>Meet keepalived - High Availability and Load Balancing in One</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/keepalived-ha-loadbalancer/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Meet keepalived - High Availability and Load Balancing in One" /><published>2021-12-11T07:00:00-06:00</published> <updated>2021-12-11T10:50:11-06:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/keepalived-ha-loadbalancer/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/keepalived-ha-loadbalancer/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="homelab" /> <summary> In my quest to make my services highly available I decided to use keepalived. keepalived is a framework for both load balancing and high availability that implements VRRP. This is a protocol that you see on some routers and has been implemented in keepalived. It creates a Virtual IP (or VIP, or floating IP) that acts as a gateway to route traffic to all participating hosts. This VIP that c... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>HomeLab Services Tour Late 2021 - What am I Self-Hosting in my HomeLab?</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/homelab-services-tour-2021/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="HomeLab Services Tour Late 2021 - What am I Self-Hosting in my HomeLab?" /><published>2021-12-04T07:00:00-06:00</published> <updated>2021-12-04T07:00:00-06:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/homelab-services-tour-2021/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/homelab-services-tour-2021/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="homelab" /> <summary> After showing off my Home Lab hardware in my late 2021 tour, many of you asked what services are self-hosted in this stack. This is always a moving target so I decided it was time to share which services I am running here at home. Today, we walk through everything I am hosting including: Dashboard, Hypervisor, Virtualization, Containerization, Network Attached Storage (NAS), DNS, Network ... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Meet Grafana LOKI, a Log Aggregation System for Everything</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/grafana-loki/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Meet Grafana LOKI, a Log Aggregation System for Everything" /><published>2021-11-20T07:00:00-06:00</published> <updated>2021-12-07T21:09:16-06:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/grafana-loki/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/grafana-loki/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="homelab" /> <summary> I’ve been on a quest to find a new logging system. I’ve use quite a few in the past, some open source, some proprietary, and some home grown, but recently I’ve decided to switch. I’ve switched to Grafana Loki for all of my logs for all of my systems - this includes machines, devices, docker systems and hosts, and my all of my kubernetes clusters. If you’re thinking of using Grafana and are... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Installing Grafana Loki with Helm on Kubernetes</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/grafana-loki-kubernetes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Installing Grafana Loki with Helm on Kubernetes" /><published>2021-11-20T06:00:00-06:00</published> <updated>2021-11-23T19:20:32-06:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/grafana-loki-kubernetes/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/grafana-loki-kubernetes/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="kubernetes" /> <summary> In my previous video (Meet Grafana LOKI, a log aggregation system for everything and post, I promised that I would also explain how to install Granfana Loki on Kubernetes using helm. If you’re looking to set this up in docker-compose, be sure to check out this video Installing helm Think of helm as a package manager for kubernetes. It’a an easy way to bundle and deploy config to kubernetes w... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Techno Tim HomeLab and NEW Server Room Tour! (Late 2021)</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/homelab-tour-2021/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Techno Tim HomeLab and NEW Server Room Tour! (Late 2021)" /><published>2021-11-06T08:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2021-11-23T18:44:11-06:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/homelab-tour-2021/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/homelab-tour-2021/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="homelab" /> <summary> Well, here it is! My Late 2021 Server Rack and HomeLab tour! This is a special one because I just revamped and remodeled a spot in the basement for my new data center / server room (still picking out a name for it). I’ve upgraded, replaced, added, and consolidated quite a bit since my last tour! New servers, new networking, new UPS, new Raspberry Pi, and even a whole entire wall of tech g... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Virtualize Windows 11 with Proxmox the Right Way!</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/windows-11-proxmox/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Virtualize Windows 11 with Proxmox the Right Way!" /><published>2021-10-22T08:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2021-12-04T23:22:20-06:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/windows-11-proxmox/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/windows-11-proxmox/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="homelab" /> <summary> Windows 11 is here and with it comes new hardware requirements. These requirements not only affect physical hardware but also virtual hardware too. The TPM 2.0 requirement for Windows 11 is shaking the tech community, HomeLab community, and even virtualization too. Well have no fear, today we’re going to virtualize Windows 11 with a virtual TPM chip! We’re going to create a virtual machi... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Meet Uptime Kuma, a Fancy Open Source Uptime Monitor for all your HomeLab Monitoring Needs</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/uptime-kuma/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Meet Uptime Kuma, a Fancy Open Source Uptime Monitor for all your HomeLab Monitoring Needs" /><published>2021-10-03T10:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2021-12-04T23:16:19-06:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/uptime-kuma/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/uptime-kuma/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="self-hosted" /> <summary> You’ve spun up lots of self-hosted services in your HomeLab but you haven’t set up monitoring and alerting yet. We’ll be glad you waited because today well set up Uptime Kuma to do just that. Uptime Kuma is a self-hosted, open source, fancy uptime monitoring and alerting system. It can monitor HTTP, HTTP with keyword, TCP, Ping, and even DNS systems! https://github.com/louislam/uptime-kum... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Network UPS Tools (NUT) Ultimate Guide</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/NUT-server-guide/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Network UPS Tools (NUT) Ultimate Guide" /><published>2021-09-25T10:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2021-12-05T21:59:39-06:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/NUT-server-guide/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/NUT-server-guide/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="homelab" /> <summary> Meet NUT Server, or Network UPS Tools. It’s an open UPS networking monitoring tool that runs on many different operating systems and processors. This means you can run the server on Linux, MacOS, or BSD and run the client on Windows, MacOS, Linux, and more. It’ perfect for your Pi, server, or desktop. It works with hundreds of UPS devices, PDUs, and many other power management systems. T... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Meet File Browser, a Small but Mighty Web File Browser</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/meet-file-browser/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Meet File Browser, a Small but Mighty Web File Browser" /><published>2021-09-04T10:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2021-12-04T23:16:19-06:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/meet-file-browser/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/meet-file-browser/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="self-hosted" /> <summary> Meet File Browser, an open source, self-hosted alternative to services like Dropbox and other web based file browsers. Today we’ll configure a containerized version of File Browser and have you up and going in just a few minutes. We’ll also walk through creating, editing, moving, copying, and even sharing files and folders so that you get a better understanding about what File Browser is al... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>How to Install Docker and Docker Compose</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/docker-compose-install/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Install Docker and Docker Compose" /><published>2021-08-14T11:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2021-12-21T11:23:51-06:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/docker-compose-install/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/docker-compose-install/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="docker" /> <summary> Install Docker If you have an existing version of Docker install, it might be best to remove it first. See the cleaning up section at the end sudo apt-get update sudo apt-get install \ apt-transport-https \ ca-certificates \ curl \ gnupg \ lsb-release curl -fsSL https://download.docker.com/linux/ubuntu/gpg | sudo gpg --dearmor -o /usr/share/keyrings/docker-archive-keyring.gpg ... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Self-Hosted, DIY, Open Source Alternative to Linktree</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/open-source-linktree-alt/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Self-Hosted, DIY, Open Source Alternative to Linktree" /><published>2021-08-14T11:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2021-12-04T23:22:20-06:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/open-source-linktree-alt/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/open-source-linktree-alt/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="self-hosted" /> <summary> Meet LittleLink &amp;amp; LittleLink-Server - a DIY, self hosted, and open source alternative to the popular service Linktree. This web site inside of a container allows you to create and host your own web site with all of your social information and links, giving your followers multiple ways to connect with you! In this video we talk about what LittleLink-Server is, what it does, and how to c... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>All the Secrets to Creating My Tech YouTube Channel</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/how-i-create-my-content/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="All the Secrets to Creating My Tech YouTube Channel" /><published>2021-07-31T15:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2021-12-04T23:16:19-06:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/how-i-create-my-content/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/how-i-create-my-content/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="vlog" /> <summary> People have asked how I’ve been able to create and grow a Tech YouTube channel and what my process is when planning, filming, editing, and producing content. Today we talk about just that. All my secrets unveiled as we celebrate 50,000 subscribers in this behind the scenes look. Thank you so much! Watch Video (see video description for gear links) </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Before you upgrade to Proxmox 7, please consider this...</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/proxmox-7/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Before you upgrade to Proxmox 7, please consider this..." /><published>2021-07-10T14:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2021-12-04T23:22:20-06:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/proxmox-7/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/proxmox-7/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="proxmox" /> <summary> As you may know, proxmox is my current choice for a hypervisor. Proxmox 7 is here and comes with a host of new features! In this video we’re cover all of the new features in Proxmox 7 as well as how to upgrade your Proxmox server safely. We’ll also cover all of the “scary” prompts you get while upgrading as well as some of the ways to make sure your upgrade is successful. So, if you’re think... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Linux desktop, inside of a container, inside of a browser??? Yes. A Webtop.</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/webtop-container/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Linux desktop, inside of a container, inside of a browser??? Yes. A Webtop." /><published>2021-06-20T09:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2021-12-04T23:16:19-06:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/webtop-container/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/webtop-container/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="self-hosted" /> <summary> Have you ever thought about running a Linux desktop inside of a container? Me neither until I found this awesome project from LinuxServer called Webtops. A webtop is a technology stack that allows you to run Ubuntu or Alpine Linux within a container that is fully accessible from a browser. This allows you to use most Linux features with a container with a fraction of the cost of resources.... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>2 Factor Auth and Single Sign on with Authelia</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/authelia-traefik/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2 Factor Auth and Single Sign on with Authelia" /><published>2021-06-05T09:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2021-12-04T23:22:20-06:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/authelia-traefik/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/authelia-traefik/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="traefik" /> <summary> Authelia is an open source Single Sign On and 2FA companion for reverse proxies. It helps you secure your endpoints with single factor and 2 factor auth. It works with Nginx, Traefik, and HA proxy. Today, we’ll configure Authelia with Portainer and Traefik and have 2 Factor up and running with brute force protection! Watch Video Traefik Authelia will work with other reverse proxies but ... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Is adding 3 MILLION domains to your Pi-Hole Block List a good thing?</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/pi-hole-blocklists/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Is adding 3 MILLION domains to your Pi-Hole Block List a good thing?" /><published>2021-05-08T09:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2021-06-05T09:35:10-05:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/pi-hole-blocklists/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/pi-hole-blocklists/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="homelab" /> <summary> In some of my previous Pi-Hole videos many of you spotted my blocklist with over a millions sites added and you wondered how you can do the same. Well, today I show you how to block more ads, block more tracking, block more malware, and block more telemetry with these community lists. Bonus (and spoiler alert) I show you how to add 3.5 million! Thanks to Firebog for the great lists firebog... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Put Wildcard Certificates and SSL on EVERYTHING</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/traefik-portainer-ssl/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Put Wildcard Certificates and SSL on EVERYTHING" /><published>2021-04-24T09:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2021-12-04T23:22:20-06:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/traefik-portainer-ssl/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/traefik-portainer-ssl/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="traefik" /> <summary> Today, we’re going to use SSL for everything. No more self-sign certs. No more http. No more hosting things on odd ports. We’re going all in with SSL for our internal services and our external services too. We going to set up a reverse proxy using Traefik, Portainer, and use that to get wildcard certificates from Let’s Encrypt. Join me and let’s secure all the things. Watch Video Docke... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Using Pi-Hole for Local DNS - Fast, Simple, and Easy Guide</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/pi-hole-dns/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Using Pi-Hole for Local DNS - Fast, Simple, and Easy Guide" /><published>2021-04-17T09:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2021-12-04T23:16:19-06:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/pi-hole-dns/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/pi-hole-dns/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="homelab" /> <summary> Pi-Hole is a wonderful ad blocking DNS sever for your network, but did you know you can also use it for a Local DNS server? In this fast, simple, and easy guide we’ll walk through how to create DNS Entries (A Records) for the clients on your network and also set up Aliases (pointers to A Records) so that you can start using DNS at home instead of relying on IP addresses. Watch Video command... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Monitoring Your Kubernetes Cluster with Grafana, Prometheus, and Alertmanager</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/rancher-monitoring/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Monitoring Your Kubernetes Cluster with Grafana, Prometheus, and Alertmanager" /><published>2021-04-10T09:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2021-04-10T09:00:00-05:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/rancher-monitoring/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/rancher-monitoring/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="kubernetes" /> <category term="rancher" /> <summary> Today in this step by step guide, we’ll set up Grafana, Prometheus, and Alertmanager to monitor your Kubernetes cluster. This can be set up really quickly using helm or the Rancher UI. We’ll install and configure, set up some dashboards, and even set up some alerts using Slack. All this and more in this simple to follow, easy tutorial. Setting up Grafana and Prometheus has never been so e... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Configuring Traefik 2 Ingress for Kubernetes</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/k3s-traefik-rancher/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Configuring Traefik 2 Ingress for Kubernetes" /><published>2021-04-08T09:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2021-12-05T21:56:53-06:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/k3s-traefik-rancher/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/k3s-traefik-rancher/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="kubernetes" /> <category term="rancher" /> <summary> About No video currently exists for this (yet) This guide is for installing traefik 2 on k3s. If you’re not using rancher, that’s fine, just skip to Reconfiguring k3s It assumes you have followed: HIGH AVAILABILITY k3s (Kubernetes) in minutes! High Availability Rancher on a Kubernetes Cluster There is a little bit of “undoing” we’ll have to do since k3s ships with tr... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Everything you need to know about the NEW Rancher UI</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/rancher-new-ui/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Everything you need to know about the NEW Rancher UI" /><published>2021-04-03T09:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2021-12-04T23:16:19-06:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/rancher-new-ui/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/rancher-new-ui/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="kubernetes" /> <category term="rancher" /> <summary> Today we’re going to talk about the new Cluster Explorer in Rancher. The Cluster Explorer is the new fancy user interface that will replace the old Cluster Manager. The new UI contains lots of new areas to explore, from new dashboards to new workload and deployment views, to service discovery, to storage to RBAC, and more. If you’ve been hesitant to use the new UI, no need to worry, we all... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Multi-CPU Architecture Kubernetes Cluster with a Raspberry Pi</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/multi-arch-k3s-rpi/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Multi-CPU Architecture Kubernetes Cluster with a Raspberry Pi" /><published>2021-03-14T09:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2021-12-04T23:16:19-06:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/multi-arch-k3s-rpi/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/multi-arch-k3s-rpi/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="kubernetes" /> <category term="k3s" /> <summary> Watch Video Building a Multi-architecture CPU Kubernetes cluster is easier than you think with k3s. In this video we’ll build a Raspberry Pi 4 with an ARM CPU and add it to our existing x86 x64 amd64 CPU Kubernetes cluster. Our foundation will be Ubuntu for ARM, then we’ll add k3s, and then join it to our cluster. We’ll also discuss how this works with Docker images built for specific CPU... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Rancher vs. Portainer - Which one should I choose?</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/rancher-vs-portainer/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rancher vs. Portainer - Which one should I choose?" /><published>2021-03-08T08:00:00-06:00</published> <updated>2021-12-04T23:22:20-06:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/rancher-vs-portainer/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/rancher-vs-portainer/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="homelab" /> <summary> Rancher vs. Portainer, which one is better” Which one should I choose? Can Portainer manager Kubernetes? Can Rancher manage Kubernetes? We answer all these questions and more in this quick, no fluff video. Side note, this is one of the most asked questions in my live streams. Please share this with anyone who asks what a Home Lab is. Watch Video </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Windows Terminal and WSL Config Fast, Simple, and Easy Guide</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/windows-terminal-wsl/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Windows Terminal and WSL Config Fast, Simple, and Easy Guide" /><published>2021-02-23T08:00:00-06:00</published> <updated>2021-02-23T08:00:00-06:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/windows-terminal-wsl/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/windows-terminal-wsl/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="homelab" /> <summary> Lots of people ask which terminal I use on Windows and how I configure it. It’s pretty simple, I use the Microsoft Windows Terminal and it’s a fantastic terminal on Windows. It is free and open source. With Windows Terminal, you can install and configure different environments for Windows and Linux. You can choose between Ubuntu or any other WSL 1 or WSL 2 (Windows Subsystem for Linux) e... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>How to Update Portainer Fast, Simple, and Easy Guide</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/portainer-update/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Update Portainer Fast, Simple, and Easy Guide" /><published>2021-02-19T08:00:00-06:00</published> <updated>2021-12-04T23:16:19-06:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/portainer-update/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/portainer-update/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="portainer" /> <summary> Updating Portainer is easy, if you know how. In this quick no fluff video, I will show you how to update any version of Portainer. This guide can be used for installing it too. Portainer is a container management system for Docker, Kubernetes, Swarm, and Azure ACI. Portainer is free and open source. Watch Video </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Containerizing HandBrake with Docker and Kubernetes</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/handbrake-docker-k8s/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Containerizing HandBrake with Docker and Kubernetes" /><published>2021-02-16T08:00:00-06:00</published> <updated>2021-02-16T08:00:00-06:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/handbrake-docker-k8s/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/handbrake-docker-k8s/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="self-hosted" /> <summary> Handbrake is a fantastic open source transcoder. It allows you to transcode, or convert, your video files into different formats. It has a nice UI that’s easy to use and helps you transcode videos very easily. It supports profiles that are optimized for your target devices. And because this is open source and cross compiled, you can run this on Windows, macOS, or Linux… but did you also kno... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>How to Create a Multiboot USB with Ventoy Fast, Simple, and Easy Guide</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/ventoy-tutorial/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Create a Multiboot USB with Ventoy Fast, Simple, and Easy Guide" /><published>2021-02-12T08:00:00-06:00</published> <updated>2021-02-12T08:00:00-06:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/ventoy-tutorial/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/ventoy-tutorial/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="homelab" /> <summary> In this quick no fluff video, I will show you how to create a multi-bootable USB drive with Ventoy that can boot all of your ISO, WIM, IMG, VHD, and EFI files. It supports both MBR and GPT partitions. This is the last USB drive you will ever need and you won’t ever need to format another one. Ventoy is free and open source. Watch Video </summary> </entry> <entry><title>The Best Way to Dual Boot Windows and Ubuntu</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/dual-boot-windows-ubuntu/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Best Way to Dual Boot Windows and Ubuntu" /><published>2021-02-08T08:00:00-06:00</published> <updated>2021-02-08T08:00:00-06:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/dual-boot-windows-ubuntu/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/dual-boot-windows-ubuntu/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="homelab" /> <summary> Dual booting Windows and Ubuntu Linux can be a pain however there are many benefits do doing this if you do it right. In this tutorial we’ll discuss how to dual boot Windows and Ubuntu on your PC or laptop in a few simple steps so that you can take advantage of all the hardware in your “best” machine with full access to your GPU. Watch Video </summary> </entry> <entry><title>I ran MY LIFE through a DEEP LEARNING algorithm and here's what came out...</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/deep-learning-my-life/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I ran MY LIFE through a DEEP LEARNING algorithm and here's what came out..." /><published>2021-02-01T08:00:00-06:00</published> <updated>2021-12-04T23:22:20-06:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/deep-learning-my-life/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/deep-learning-my-life/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="homelab" /> <summary> My life, ran against a neural network and detected by Deep Learning. If you’d like to see how this video was generated using ML and Deep Learning, check out the video here: How this video was generated Watch Video </summary> </entry> <entry><title>RTX 3090 for Machine Learning?</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/3090-machine-learning/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RTX 3090 for Machine Learning?" /><published>2021-01-30T08:00:00-06:00</published> <updated>2021-01-30T08:00:00-06:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/3090-machine-learning/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/3090-machine-learning/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="homelab" /> <summary> The NVIDIA RTX 3090 is a beast. We all know it can beat the benchmarks in gaming, but how about machine learning and neural networks? Today we walk through the RTX 3090 and then compile and run Darknet, an open source neural network, on Windows and then Ubuntu Linux and run object detection on pictures, images, and real-time video. You will be amazed at how much more you can get out of you... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>My HUGE Home Security Upgrade</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/home-security-upgrade/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My HUGE Home Security Upgrade" /><published>2021-01-16T08:00:00-06:00</published> <updated>2021-01-16T08:00:00-06:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/home-security-upgrade/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/home-security-upgrade/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="homelab" /> <summary> I am a huge fan of self hosted home security and I’ve been doing it for years. I love the idea of being able to check on my home when I am away. Also, I’ve always kept my video footage on premise (on prem) and never sent it to the cloud. It started way back with a laptop and a webcam and it evolved into self-hosting my own DVR software on a virtual machine with many PoE and wireless cameras... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Self-host your own internet speed test with LibreSpeed!</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/librespeed/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Self-host your own internet speed test with LibreSpeed!" /><published>2021-01-09T08:00:00-06:00</published> <updated>2021-01-09T08:00:00-06:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/librespeed/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/librespeed/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="self-hosted" /> <summary> Internet speed tests are full of junk, ads, tracking, and some even contain deprecated plug-ins. Who needs this when we can self-host an open source one? LibreSpeed is a lightweight speedtest implemented in JavaScript using XHR requests and web workers. It’s fast, feature rich, and supports every modern browser. Say goodbye to those other speed tests and host your own containerized in Doc... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Cloud Native Distributed Storage in Kubernetes with Longhorn</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/longhorn-install/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cloud Native Distributed Storage in Kubernetes with Longhorn" /><published>2021-01-02T08:00:00-06:00</published> <updated>2021-12-04T23:16:19-06:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/longhorn-install/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/longhorn-install/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="kubernetes" /> <category term="rancher" /> <summary> Storage in Kubernetes is hard, complicated, and messy. Configuring volumes, mounts, and persistent volumes claims and getting it right can be a challenge. It’s also challenging to manage that storage and replicate it across all your Kubernetes clusters. It’s also been very challenging to do this on bare metal, outside of a cloud provider. That’s where Longhorn comes. Longhorn is an open ... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Automate EVERYTHING with Ansible!</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/ansible-automation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Automate EVERYTHING with Ansible!" /><published>2020-12-26T08:00:00-06:00</published> <updated>2021-12-04T23:16:19-06:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/ansible-automation/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/ansible-automation/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="homelab" /> <summary> Ansible. Need I say more? Well, maybe, if you’ve never heard of it. Ansible is a simple IT automation that anyone can use. You can Automate anything with an SSH conne Watch Video You can also find a collection of playbooks here install sudo apt update sudo apt install ansible sudo apt install sshpass hosts [ubuntu] server-01 server-02 192.168.0.100 192.168.0.1002 commands command ... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>HIGH AVAILABILITY k3s (Kubernetes) in minutes!</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/k3s-ha-install/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="HIGH AVAILABILITY k3s (Kubernetes) in minutes!" /><published>2020-12-19T08:00:00-06:00</published> <updated>2021-12-04T23:16:19-06:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/k3s-ha-install/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/k3s-ha-install/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="kubernetes" /> <category term="k3s" /> <summary> Are you running Kubernetes in your homelab or in the enterprise? Do you want an easy way to manage and create Kubernetes clusters? Do you want high availability Rancher? Join me as we walk through stalling Rancher on an existing high availability k3s cluster in this step-by-step tutorial. We install Rancher, configure a load balancer, install and configure helm, install cert-manager, config... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>High Availability Rancher on kubernetes</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/rancher-ha-install/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="High Availability Rancher on kubernetes" /><published>2020-12-19T08:00:00-06:00</published> <updated>2021-12-04T23:16:19-06:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/rancher-ha-install/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/rancher-ha-install/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="kubernetes" /> <category term="rancher" /> <summary> Are you running Kubernetes in your homelab or in the enterprise? Do you want an easy way to manage and create Kubernetes clusters? Join me as we walk through installing Rancher on an existing high availability k3s cluster in this step-by-step tutorial. We install Rancher, configure a load balancer, install and configure helm, install cert-manager, configure Rancher, walk through the GUI, sca... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>High Availability Pi-Hole? Yes please!</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/ha-pi-hold-gravity-sync/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="High Availability Pi-Hole? Yes please!" /><published>2020-12-12T08:00:00-06:00</published> <updated>2021-12-21T13:00:29-06:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/ha-pi-hold-gravity-sync/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/ha-pi-hold-gravity-sync/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="self-hosted" /> <summary> Dear Pi-Hole, We love your product. It keeps our network safe from malware and other unwanted domains. While we love what is there so far, please add a feature to your core product to keep multiple servers in sync and provide high availability DNS to our whole entire network. Then, we won’t have people asking us “Is the internet down?” every time we reboot our Pi-Hole server. Until then, ... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Before I do anything on Proxmox, I do this first...</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/first-11-things-proxmox/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Before I do anything on Proxmox, I do this first..." /><published>2020-11-28T08:00:00-06:00</published> <updated>2021-11-24T22:44:55-06:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/first-11-things-proxmox/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/first-11-things-proxmox/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="proxmox" /> <summary> After setting up my Proxmox servers, there are a few thigns I do before I use them for their intended purpose. This ranges from updates, to storage, to networking and VLANS, to uploading ISOs, to clustering, and more. Join me as we pick up where the rest of the proxmox tutorials stop, and that’s everything you need to do to make these production ready (and maybe a bonus item too). Watch Vi... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>My HUGE (but small) 1U Server Upgrade</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/1u-server-upgrade/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My HUGE (but small) 1U Server Upgrade" /><published>2020-11-21T08:00:00-06:00</published> <updated>2021-12-04T23:16:19-06:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/1u-server-upgrade/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/1u-server-upgrade/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="homelab" /> <summary> I’ve been making great use of some older, bigger servers but I decided to try and build, upgrade, and migrate to some 1U servers. Join me as we unbox and build my 2 new virtualization servers! Watch Video </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Meet WireGuard, the new hotness in VPN...</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/wiregaurd-setup/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Meet WireGuard, the new hotness in VPN..." /><published>2020-11-14T08:00:00-06:00</published> <updated>2020-11-14T08:00:00-06:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/wiregaurd-setup/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/wiregaurd-setup/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="self-hosted" /> <summary> Self hosting a VPN has traditionally been hard to set up and we’ve had very few options. That is until WireGuard came about. WireGuard is an extremely simple yet fast and modern VPN that utilizes state-of-the-art cryptography. It also supports running inside of a Docker container and that’s exactly what we’ll be using in this tutorial! Watch Video </summary> </entry> <entry><title>I think I found a Dropbox replacement with Nextcloud...</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/nextcloud-setup/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I think I found a Dropbox replacement with Nextcloud..." /><published>2020-11-07T08:00:00-06:00</published> <updated>2020-11-07T08:00:00-06:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/nextcloud-setup/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/nextcloud-setup/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="self-hosted" /> <summary> Are you thinking about ditching Google apps or looking for a Dropbox replacement? Are you ready to self host your own productivity platform? Well, Nextcloud may be for you! In today’s tutorial we’ll walk though setting up Nextcloud with Docker and Kubernetes. We’ll also walk through some of the new features, installing apps from the app store, exposing this Nextcloud publicly, as well as ... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Before I do anything on Linux, I do these first...</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/fist-13-things-linux/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Before I do anything on Linux, I do these first..." /><published>2020-10-31T09:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2021-12-04T23:16:19-06:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/fist-13-things-linux/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/fist-13-things-linux/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="homelab" /> <summary> After setting up my Linux servers, there are a few things I do before I use them for their intended purpose. This ranges from security, to tools, to config. Join me as we set up our first Linux server in this tutorial and walk through setting it up proper (and maybe some bonus items sprinkled in). Watch Video Update sudo apt-get update sudo apt-get upgrade Reconfigure unattended-upgra... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Huge Network Upgrade for My Homelab</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/home-network-upgrade/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Huge Network Upgrade for My Homelab" /><published>2020-10-24T09:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2020-10-24T09:00:00-05:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/home-network-upgrade/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/home-network-upgrade/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="homelab" /> <summary> I decided to give my Home Lab a proper upgrade for 2020 and in to 2021! I finally took the plunge and went all in with a UniFi UDM Pro and a UniFi Switch PRO 24 PoE switch and they are awesome! Watch Video </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Migrate Your Databases to Kubernetes and Docker</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/migrate-database-docker-kubernetes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Migrate Your Databases to Kubernetes and Docker" /><published>2020-10-17T09:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2021-12-04T23:22:20-06:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/migrate-database-docker-kubernetes/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/migrate-database-docker-kubernetes/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="self-hosted" /> <summary> Have you been putting off migrating your database to Docker and Kubernetes like I have? Well wait no longer. It’s simple using this step-by-step tutorial. Today, we’ll move a database that’s on a virtual machine to a container that’s running in kubernetes. Oh yeah, this will also work if it’s a bare metal server too, duh. 🙂 Watch Video mysql_backup.sh #! /bin/bash BACKUP_DIR="/home" ... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>I Heard You Like GPUs in Servers... GPU Passthrough on Linux and Docker</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/gpu-passthrough-linux/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I Heard You Like GPUs in Servers... GPU Passthrough on Linux and Docker" /><published>2020-10-10T09:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2021-12-04T23:22:20-06:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/gpu-passthrough-linux/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/gpu-passthrough-linux/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="homelab" /> <summary> Do you have a lot of virtual machines? Are you running Windows, Linux, and Mac and need remote access from a single UI? Well, Apache Guacamole is for you! Apache Guacamole is a clientless remote access gateway that give you a web portal to access any of your clients over standard protocols like VNC, RDP, SSH, TELNET, and more. Join me in this step by step tutorial as we set up a self-hoste... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>I Built Something for Your Homelab...</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/broadlink-control/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I Built Something for Your Homelab..." /><published>2020-10-03T09:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2020-10-03T09:00:00-05:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/broadlink-control/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/broadlink-control/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="self-hosted" /> <summary> I am betting you have at least 3 infrared remote controls in your house. I am also willing to be you would love to automate some of these from time to time. Well don’t worry I have the solution for you! In this video we walk through setting up a self-hosted /local only Broadlink Wifi Smart Home Hub that you can use within your own home without connecting to the cloud. Added bonus, I buil... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Meet Guacamole, Your Remote Access Gateway</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/guacamole-remote-access-gateway/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Meet Guacamole, Your Remote Access Gateway" /><published>2020-09-26T09:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2020-09-26T09:00:00-05:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/guacamole-remote-access-gateway/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/guacamole-remote-access-gateway/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="self-hosted" /> <summary> Do you have a lot of virtual machines? Are you running Windows, Linux, and Mac and need remote access from a single UI? Well, Apache Guacamole is for you! Apache Guacamole is a clientless remote access gateway that give you a web portal to access any of your clients over standard protocols like VNC, RDP, SSH, TELNET, and more. Join me in this step by step tutorial as we set up a self-hoste... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Bridge Mode with UniFi Access Points</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/unifi-ap-bridge-mode/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bridge Mode with UniFi Access Points" /><published>2020-09-19T09:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2020-09-19T09:00:00-05:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/unifi-ap-bridge-mode/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/unifi-ap-bridge-mode/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="homelab" /> <summary> Do you have some places where you can’t run ethernet? Do want to extend your ethernet without pulling more cable? Well this is the guide for you. In this step-by-step tutorial we’ll use a Ubiquiti UniFi AP AC PRO and connect a second as a guest, giving use remote ethernet to a remote site! This is the pro tip guide to setting up a wireless bridge! Bonus, we’ll even do a live throughput t... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Build &amp; Deploy Your Own Code in Your Homelab!</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/self-hosted-devops-stack/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Build &amp; Deploy Your Own Code in Your Homelab!" /><published>2020-09-12T09:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2021-12-04T23:16:19-06:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/self-hosted-devops-stack/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/self-hosted-devops-stack/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="self-hosted" /> <category term="homelab" /> <summary> So you’re a software engineer or a developer who wants to self-host your own code in your own homelab? Well this is the tutorial for you! In this step-by-step guide we’ll walk through setting up a repo, building and testing our own code (with unit tests) in a self-hosted Gitlab CI runner in our CI pipeline, then we’ll build a Docker image and push it up to a container registry, then we’ll u... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>SSL, Traefik, and OAuth for Rancher! (Google, GitHub, Keycloak, Azure, and more!)</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/host-rancher-securely/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SSL, Traefik, and OAuth for Rancher! (Google, GitHub, Keycloak, Azure, and more!)" /><published>2020-09-05T09:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2020-09-05T09:00:00-05:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/host-rancher-securely/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/host-rancher-securely/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="kubernetes" /> <category term="rancher" /> <summary> Do you want to self host your Rancher UI securely in your homelab? Have you thought about putting your Rancher UI behind Traefik and your reverse proxy to get free SSL certificates using Let’s Encrypt? Do you want to make your Rancher UI available publicly and secure it using 3rd party OAuth providers like Google, GitHub, Keycloak, Okta, Shibboleth, and more? Well this is the guide for you.... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Portainer 2.0 -- Now with more Kubernetes!</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/portainer-2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Portainer 2.0 -- Now with more Kubernetes!" /><published>2020-08-29T09:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2021-12-21T11:23:51-06:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/portainer-2/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/portainer-2/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="portainer" /> <summary> What’s new in Portainer 2.0? Well, a ton. With the release of Portainer 2 you now have the option to install Kubernetes. This makes installing, managing, and deploying Kubenetes really easy. In this step by step tutorial, we’ll start with nothing and end up with a fully working Portainer 2 server running Kubernetes. We’ll set up k3s using k3d, install kubectl, and then spin up Portainer.... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Self-Host All Your Homelab Services with DuckDNS -- Free Dynamic DNS Running on Docker</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/duck-dns/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Self-Host All Your Homelab Services with DuckDNS -- Free Dynamic DNS Running on Docker" /><published>2020-08-22T09:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2020-08-22T09:00:00-05:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/duck-dns/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/duck-dns/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="self-hosted" /> <summary> Are you trying to access your self-hosted services outside of your firewall? Are you tired of trying to remember your IP when away, or worse yet, having your ISP change your IP address? Have you not purchased a domain yet but want to access your own personal VPN? If you answered “YES” to any of these, join me as we walk through this step-by-step tutorial and set up DuckDNS, the free dynami... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Self-Hosting Your Homelab Services with SSL -- Let's Encrypt, MetalLB, Traefik, Rancher, Kubernetes</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/reverse-proxy-kubernetes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Self-Hosting Your Homelab Services with SSL -- Let's Encrypt, MetalLB, Traefik, Rancher, Kubernetes" /><published>2020-08-15T09:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2020-08-15T09:00:00-05:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/reverse-proxy-kubernetes/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/reverse-proxy-kubernetes/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="kubernetes" /> <category term="rancher" /> <summary> Are you self-hosting lots of services at home in your homelab? Have you been port forwarding or using VPN to access your self-hosted services wishing you had certificates so that you can access them securely over SSL? Well after this video, you can! In this step by step tutorial we’ll walk through setting up Rancher and Kubernetes with a reverse proxy, Kubernetes Ingress, MetalLB, Traefik,... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Self-Host Code Server in Your Homelab -- VS Code in a Browser!</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/code-server-self-host/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Self-Host Code Server in Your Homelab -- VS Code in a Browser!" /><published>2020-08-08T09:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2020-08-08T09:00:00-05:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/code-server-self-host/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/code-server-self-host/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="self-hosted" /> <summary> Have you ever wanted to run VS Code in your browser? What if you had access to your terminal and could pull and commit code as well as push it up to GitHub all from a browser or tablet? That’s exactly what code server does! In this tutorial we’ll walk through step by step of how to install and configure code server to get it self-hosted in your homelab. We’ll start with bare metal and vir... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>How to Upgrade FreeNAS to TrueNAS</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/upgrade-freenas-to-truenas/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Upgrade FreeNAS to TrueNAS" /><published>2020-08-01T09:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2020-08-01T09:00:00-05:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/upgrade-freenas-to-truenas/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/upgrade-freenas-to-truenas/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="truenas" /> <summary> Want to migrate FreeNAS to TrueNAS today? It’s simple using this step by step tutorial. We’ll walk through how to upgrade FreeNAS to TreNAS CORE. We’ll cover upgrading FreeNAS to TrueNAS on a physical machine (bare metal) as well as a virtualized install of FreeNAS. We’ll prepare our services, jails, plugins, virtual machines, pools, and disks for the migration and then upgrade each. We’l... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Proxmox Backup Server Install Tutorial</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/proxmox-backup-server/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Proxmox Backup Server Install Tutorial" /><published>2020-07-25T09:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2020-07-25T09:00:00-05:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/proxmox-backup-server/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/proxmox-backup-server/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="proxmox" /> <summary> Proxmox Backup Server is an enterprise-class client-server backup software that backs up virtual machines, containers, and physical hosts. In this step by step tutorial, we install and configure Proxmox Backup Server (PBS) and back up all of our virtual machines. We’ll start with nothing and end up with a fully functional Proxmox Backup Server with a ZFS datastore you can use to back up and ... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Homelab Services Tour -- What am I running on my Homelab?</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/homelab-services-tour-2020/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Homelab Services Tour -- What am I running on my Homelab?" /><published>2020-07-18T09:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2020-07-18T09:00:00-05:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/homelab-services-tour-2020/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/homelab-services-tour-2020/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="homelab" /> <summary> In my homelab tour, I showed you my hardware and network setup that powers all the infrastructure at home. Then, many of you asked which services I am hosting on this hardware. Well, here it is. This is a tour of all the self hosted services I have running in my Homelab. Watch Video </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Techno Tim Homelab Tour -- Server Rack and Network</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/homelab-hardware-tour/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Techno Tim Homelab Tour -- Server Rack and Network" /><published>2020-07-11T09:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2020-07-11T09:00:00-05:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/homelab-hardware-tour/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/homelab-hardware-tour/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="homelab" /> <summary> You asked for a tour of my homelab, well here it is. In this tour I will take you through my home server rack and network setup. This includes my all of my home networking equipment, my servers, disk array, and everything else in my server rack. Watch Video </summary> </entry> <entry><title>How to Build a Slack Bot</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/slack-bot/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Build a Slack Bot" /><published>2020-07-04T09:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2020-07-04T09:00:00-05:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/slack-bot/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/slack-bot/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="coding" /> <summary> Slack is a great chat and communication tool used by small and large businesses as well as personal use. Slack has a great API and great official Node JS clients that help you automate many features of Slack. If you’re thinking of building a bot for Slack, be sure to follow this step by step tutorial on how to build a Slack bot in JavaScript using the Slack API and the Node Slack SDK. With ... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>How to Upgrade, Backup, and Restore Rancher 2</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/rancher-2-upgrade-backup-restore/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Upgrade, Backup, and Restore Rancher 2" /><published>2020-06-27T09:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2021-04-14T21:39:35-05:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/rancher-2-upgrade-backup-restore/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/rancher-2-upgrade-backup-restore/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="kubernetes" /> <category term="rancher" /> <summary> It use to be hard to back up Rancher, but with Rancher 2 it’s super simple. Upgrading, backing up, and restoring your Rancher server should be part of your regular routine. Join me in this tutorial as we walk through backing up, upgrading, and restoring a single node Rancher Docker install in just a couple of minutes. Trust me, you’ll feel better after you do. Watch Video Need to... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Meet Heimdall, Your Homelab Application Dashboard</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/heimdall-dashboard/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Meet Heimdall, Your Homelab Application Dashboard" /><published>2020-06-20T09:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2020-06-20T09:00:00-05:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/heimdall-dashboard/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/heimdall-dashboard/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="self-hosted" /> <summary> Tired of bookmarking all of your self-hosted services only to lose them? Want access to all your sites from anywhere in the world? Well, Heimdall can help with a clean, responsive, and beautiful dashboard for all of your Homelab services. So join me in this tutorial as we install and configure Heimdall on Docker and Kubernetes and build a dashboard with live icons. Watch Video </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Home Assistant on Docker and Kubernetes (Open Source Home Automation)</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/home-assistant/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Home Assistant on Docker and Kubernetes (Open Source Home Automation)" /><published>2020-06-13T09:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2021-04-12T22:52:26-05:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/home-assistant/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/home-assistant/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="self-hosted" /> <summary> Are you ready to start automating your smart home with the power of open source? Do you already have Home Assistant running but need a little more power than a Raspberry Pi? If so, join me in this easy to follow, step by step tutorial on installing Home Assistant on Docker, Kubernetes, and Rancher. We’ll set it up, walk through and configure the UI, and then move on to configure some Wemo s... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Virtualize vs. Containerize (Which should I choose?)</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/virtualize-vs-containerize/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Virtualize vs. Containerize (Which should I choose?)" /><published>2020-06-06T09:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2020-06-06T09:00:00-05:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/virtualize-vs-containerize/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/virtualize-vs-containerize/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="homelab" /> <summary> Should I virtualize this? Should I containerize this? These are great questions to ask yourself when spinning up self-hosted services in your Homelab environment. We’ll review my previous video (20 Ways to Use a Virtual Machine (and other ideas for your homelab https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pxwUXJmAER4) and decide which should run in a Docker container, which should be virtualized with P... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>PiHole on Docker and Kubernetes (I almost gave up)</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/pihole-containerized/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="PiHole on Docker and Kubernetes (I almost gave up)" /><published>2020-05-30T09:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2020-05-30T09:00:00-05:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/pihole-containerized/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/pihole-containerized/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="self-hosted" /> <summary> We know you’ve heard of Pihole and we know you are probably aware of how to install it but… have you tried running it on Docker and Kubernetes using Rancher? Have you configured it for pfSense? Don’t worry, I figured out all the hard stuff for you. So let’s consolidate some hardware and services. Watch Video Ubuntu Fix sudo apt-get update sudo apt-get install resolvconf sudo nano /e... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>4 Ways to Install Plex (one is unexpected)</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/plex-containerized/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="4 Ways to Install Plex (one is unexpected)" /><published>2020-05-23T09:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2020-05-23T09:00:00-05:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/plex-containerized/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/plex-containerized/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="self-hosted" /> <summary> I’m a huge fan of virtualization and containerization (if you couldn’t tell already)! Today, we’ll walk though the various ways to install Plex step-by-step. We also see how easy it is to get Plex running on Docker and Kubernetes using Rancher. Watch Video Id for Container Get Id and Group Id id yourusername Should see something like this: uid=1001(technotim) gid=1001(technotim) grou... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>How to Virtualize Your Home Router / Firewall Using pfSense</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/proxmox-pfsense/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Virtualize Your Home Router / Firewall Using pfSense" /><published>2020-05-16T09:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2020-05-16T09:00:00-05:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/proxmox-pfsense/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/proxmox-pfsense/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="homelab" /> <summary> It’s time to say goodbye to your home router and start virtualizing it using Proxmox and pfSense. pfSense Community Edition Download: https://www.pfsense.org/download/ Get started with Proxmox today: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7OVaWaqO2aU Watch Video Enable PCI Passthrough https://pve.proxmox.com/wiki/PCI(e)_Passthrough </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Setup and Best Settings for Streamlabs OBS on Mac</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/streamlabs-mac/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Setup and Best Settings for Streamlabs OBS on Mac" /><published>2020-05-09T09:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2020-05-09T09:00:00-05:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/streamlabs-mac/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/streamlabs-mac/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="streaming" /> <summary> Streamlabs OBS for MacOS is here! In this video we’ll walk through setting up Streamlabs step by step. We’ll install Streamlabs OBS, set up desktop audio with iShowU Audio Capture so you can capture desktop audio, configure our webcam and game capture with a Cam Link, set up our alerts, configure the best possible streaming settings for Streamlabs, adjust our streaming layout, and go live. ... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>How to Build a Twitch Bot Using TMI.JS (a moderator bot)</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/twitch-bot/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Build a Twitch Bot Using TMI.JS (a moderator bot)" /><published>2020-05-03T09:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2021-04-17T11:23:28-05:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/twitch-bot/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/twitch-bot/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="coding" /> <summary> Let’s build a bot! Not a bad bot like a view bot, but bot for good. Let’s build a Twitch moderator bot using tmi.js! The Twitch API is powerful and and already has lots of great bots however no bot has the flexibility of creating your own! In this video I will show you how to build a Twitch bot using TMI.JS from start to finish. You’ll see how to use the developer portal, set up oauth, s... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>20 Ways to Use a Virtual Machine (and other ideas for your homelab)</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/20-ways-virtual-machine/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="20 Ways to Use a Virtual Machine (and other ideas for your homelab)" /><published>2020-04-26T09:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2020-04-26T09:00:00-05:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/20-ways-virtual-machine/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/20-ways-virtual-machine/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="homelab" /> <summary> Looking for new ideas on how to use your virtual machines? Well, here’s the top 20 ways to use your virtual machines in your homelab. Watch Video </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Convert ANY Desk to a STANDING Desk: Home Office Upgrade</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/office-upgrade/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Convert ANY Desk to a STANDING Desk: Home Office Upgrade" /><published>2020-04-19T09:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2020-04-19T09:00:00-05:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/office-upgrade/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/office-upgrade/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="vlog" /> <summary> I decided to tear apart our office and convert my old Ikea hack table tops into a standing desk. Oh, and I also clamped on 3 - 27” 1440p gaming monitors while I was at it 😉 Watch Video </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Docker, Rancher, Kubernetes... Minecraft? (Setup and Install Tutorial)</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/docker-rancher-kubernetes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Docker, Rancher, Kubernetes... Minecraft? (Setup and Install Tutorial)" /><published>2020-04-09T09:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2021-04-14T21:36:44-05:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/docker-rancher-kubernetes/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/docker-rancher-kubernetes/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="homelab" /> <summary> If you want to set up Kubernetes at home using Rancher to run Docker containers, this is the guide for you. This is a step by step tutorial of how to install and configure Rancher, Docker, and Kubernetes for your homelab. In this video we set up and configure a Minecraft server in just a matter of minutes with some enterprise like features. You can use this same process to spin up other Doc... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>How to Update Proxmox VE (No subscription required)</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/proxmox-update/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Update Proxmox VE (No subscription required)" /><published>2020-04-02T09:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2021-04-12T23:21:18-05:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/proxmox-update/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/proxmox-update/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="proxmox" /> <summary> Have you been thinking about updating your Proxmox VE server? Well, what are you waiting for? Upgrade your Proxmox server in your home lab in just a few minutes with this step-by-step tutorial! Watch Video Edit /etc/apt/sources.list deb http://ftp.us.debian.org/debian buster main contrib deb http://ftp.us.debian.org/debian buster-updates main contrib # security updates deb http://secur... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Remote Gaming! (and Video Encoding using Proxmox and GPU Passthrough)</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/gpu-passthrough/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Remote Gaming! (and Video Encoding using Proxmox and GPU Passthrough)" /><published>2020-03-26T09:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2021-04-13T20:04:45-05:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/gpu-passthrough/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/gpu-passthrough/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="homelab" /> <summary> Are you looking to build a remote gaming machine and passthrough your GPU to a virtual machine? Do you want to use GPU acceleration for transcoding Plex or Adobe Media Encoder? Do you dream of setting up Steam Link or Remote Play In Home Streaming and streaming games to any screen in your house? If so, this complete step-by-step guide of how to passthrough your Nvidia or AMD video card thr... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Virtualize Ubuntu Server with Proxmox VE</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/proxmox-ubuntu-server/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Virtualize Ubuntu Server with Proxmox VE" /><published>2020-03-20T09:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2020-03-20T09:00:00-05:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/proxmox-ubuntu-server/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/proxmox-ubuntu-server/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="proxmox" /> <summary> Do you need to virtualize Ubuntu Server with Proxmox? Join me as we install and configure Ubuntu Server LTS on Proxmox VE step-by-step using the best performance options. Watch Video </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Virtualize Windows 10 with Proxmox VE</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/proxmox-windows/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Virtualize Windows 10 with Proxmox VE" /><published>2020-03-18T09:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2020-03-18T09:00:00-05:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/proxmox-windows/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/proxmox-windows/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="proxmox" /> <summary> Do you need to virtualize Windows 10 with Proxmox? Join me as we install and configure Windows 10 on Proxmox VE step-by-step using the best performance options. Watch Video </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Proxmox VE Install and Setup Tutorial</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/proxmox-setup/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Proxmox VE Install and Setup Tutorial" /><published>2020-03-14T09:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2020-03-14T09:00:00-05:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/proxmox-setup/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/proxmox-setup/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="homelab" /> <summary> Do you need to virtualize something at home? Thinking of building your own Homelab? (The answer is YES). Join me as we install and configure Proxmox VE step-by-step. Watch Video </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Setting Up Windows for JavaScript Development THE RIGHT WAY (WSL Terminal NVM Node Yarn VS Code ZSH)</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/windows-developer-setup/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Setting Up Windows for JavaScript Development THE RIGHT WAY (WSL Terminal NVM Node Yarn VS Code ZSH)" /><published>2020-03-12T09:00:00-05:00</published> <updated>2020-03-12T09:00:00-05:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/windows-developer-setup/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/windows-developer-setup/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="coding" /> <summary> You want to get started developing JavaScript with NodeJS, ReactJS, or AngularJS but you’re not sure how to get started? This is a complete, step by step guide on how to configure your Windows machines for JavaScript development the right way. You’ll learn how to install and configure Windows, the new Windows Terminal, WSL, Ubuntu, ZSH with Oh My ZSH, yarn, NPM, NVM, NodeJS, and VS Code. ... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>How To Create an iSCSI Target with TrueNAS</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/iscsi-truenas/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How To Create an iSCSI Target with TrueNAS" /><published>2020-03-06T08:00:00-06:00</published> <updated>2020-03-06T08:00:00-06:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/iscsi-truenas/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/iscsi-truenas/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="truenas" /> <summary> Setting up iSCSI with TrueNAS and Windows 10 is super simple with TrueNAS. This is an easy way to have a hard drive installed on your machine that isn’t really attached, it lives on the network. Watch Video </summary> </entry> <entry><title>How to Install and Virtualize TrueNAS with Proxmox</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/virtualize-truenas/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Install and Virtualize TrueNAS with Proxmox" /><published>2020-03-01T08:00:00-06:00</published> <updated>2020-03-01T08:00:00-06:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/virtualize-truenas/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/virtualize-truenas/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="truenas" /> <summary> Do you want a DIY NAS? Do you want to set up TrueNAS? Have you considered virtualizing TrueNAS with Proxmox? In this video we’ll walk through installing and setting up TrueNAS and configure a samba share for Windows. We’ll also install it on a virtual server using ProxmoxVE that’s running in my Homelab. Both are free and open source. Watch Video </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Let's Build a Discord Bot Using DiscordJS - Moderator Bot</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/discord-bot/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Let's Build a Discord Bot Using DiscordJS - Moderator Bot" /><published>2020-02-17T08:00:00-06:00</published> <updated>2020-02-17T08:00:00-06:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/discord-bot/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/discord-bot/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="coding" /> <summary> Let’s build a bot! Not a bad bot like a view bot, but bot for good. Let’s build a discord moderator bot using discord.js! Discord is powerful chat + video client and already has lots of great bots however no bot has the flexibility of creating your own! In this video I will show you how to build a discord bot using DiscordJS from start to finish. You’ll see how to use the developer porta... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Touch Portal vs. Stream Deck</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/touchportal-vs-streamdeck/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Touch Portal vs. Stream Deck" /><published>2020-02-02T08:00:00-06:00</published> <updated>2020-02-02T08:00:00-06:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/touchportal-vs-streamdeck/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/touchportal-vs-streamdeck/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="streaming" /> <summary> Let’s compare Touch Portal to Stream Deck. We’ll walk through some of the similarities and differences between the free software Touch Portal and the Stream Deck hardware/software combination. We’ll see if we can set up, configure in a step by step guide, and clone our Stream Deck interface for OBS using Touch Portal and a mobile device, we’ll review features and experiences, then we’ll cho... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Upgrade Your ROOM (One of the most OVERLOOKED stream upgrades!)</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/upgrade-your-room/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Upgrade Your ROOM (One of the most OVERLOOKED stream upgrades!)" /><published>2020-01-20T08:00:00-06:00</published> <updated>2020-01-20T08:00:00-06:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/upgrade-your-room/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/upgrade-your-room/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="streaming" /> <summary> There are so many upgrades out there for streaming, what do I start with? Video card? Microphone? Audio? CPU? RAM? Lights? I started with one that is overlooked by many streamers, and it’s the room I stream in. So come along with me as give a tour of my stream room makeover! Hopefully this video gives you some stream background ideas for sofas, lights, smart LED lights, accent lighting, co... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>BEST OBS Streaming Settings 2020! 🔴 (Quality, Frame Rate, Bit Rate, Audio, 1080p 60/FPS &amp; MORE!)</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/obs-best-settings/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="BEST OBS Streaming Settings 2020! 🔴 (Quality, Frame Rate, Bit Rate, Audio, 1080p 60/FPS &amp; MORE!)" /><published>2020-01-14T08:00:00-06:00</published> <updated>2021-04-13T22:50:40-05:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/obs-best-settings/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/obs-best-settings/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="streaming" /> <summary> Do you want the best settings for OBS in 2020? This is the ultimate OBS settings guide with the BEST OBS settings for streaming Fortnite, Just Chatting APEX Legends, PUBG, or really ANY game. This video includes the best settings for quality, frame rate, bit rate, and audio for streaming at 60 frames per second (FPS) at 1080p (max settings for streamers). This guide works with OBS Studio, S... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>GoXLR WITH WIRELESS HEADSET - Connect ANY wireless bluetooth headphones</title><link href="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/goxlr-wireless/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="GoXLR WITH WIRELESS HEADSET - Connect ANY wireless bluetooth headphones" /><published>2020-01-07T08:00:00-06:00</published> <updated>2021-04-17T11:23:28-05:00</updated> <id>https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/goxlr-wireless/</id> <content src="https://techno-tim.github.io/posts/goxlr-wireless/" /> <author> <name>Techno Tim</name> </author> <category term="streaming" /> <summary> Connect any wireless headset to a GoXLR or GoXLR mini. In this video, I show you how you can connect any pair of wireless bluetooth headphones to a GoXLR or GoXLR mini. They can be AirPods, Beats, Beats Wireless Pro, Bose, or any other wireless bluetooth headset. You can use this bluetooth adapter transmitter to stream while using the GoXLR or GoXLR mini. I bought these products with my ow... </summary> </entry> </feed>
